Guide to the Richard C. Burns archive of Overtone Records, Inc.
Yale University Music Library
- Overtone and Richard C. Burns digitized and remastered recordings, Series V
  - Boatwright, Howard: Various works, 1967–1988
    - First processing stage (Box 27, Item 5)
    - Second processing stage (Box 27, Item 6)
      Does not list Mass S. U. singers.
  - Boatwright, Howard: Various works, 1963-1979, undated (Box 27, Item 7)
    Boatwright, Howard: Symphony, The Syracuse Symphony Orchestra, Christopher Keene, conductor (recorded 1979 Jan 12 [?]); Serenade for clarinet, horn, violin, and violoncello; Christmas Cantata, Variations for Orchestra; Trio for strings; Canticle of the Sun. Spring choral festical of secondary schools (recorded 1963 Apr 23), Helen Boatwright, soprano.
  - Brahms, Johannes: Various Works, 1958 April 19 (Box 27, Item 8)
    Brahms, Johannes: Requiem; Paul Hindemith: Canticle to Hope. Helen Boatwright, soprano, Margaret Tobias, mezzo-soprano, Banjamin de Laoche, baritone. Smith College Glee Club, Yale Glee Club, members of the Yale Band, Yale University Orchestra; Howard Boatwright, conductor. Yale HSR-2 stereo master.
  - Buxtehude, Dietrich: Various works, 1954 May 5 (Box 27, Item 9)
    Buxtehude, Dietrich: Cantatas -- Herr auf dich traue ich; Liebster, meine Seele saget; Jesu, meine Freude; Singet dem Herrn; Trauermusik auf dem Tod des Johannes Buxtehude; Lauda Sion salvatorem. Helen Boatwright, soprano, Charlene Peterson, soprano; instumental ensemble of the Yale School of Music; Howard Boatwright, conductor. More musical and technical information in storage case.
  - Centennial concert, Yale School of Music, 1954 November 5 (Box 27, Item 10)
    David Stanley Smith: Prince Hal Overture; Douglas Moore: Symphony in A major; Charles Ives: Symphone no. 3; Quincy Porter: Concerto for Two Pianos and Orchestra, Arthur Whittemore, piano, Jack Lowe, piano. The Yale University Orchestra, Howard Boatwright, conductor, Quncy Porter, conductor. Stereo.
  - Various works, 1952, undated (Box 27, Item 11)
    Delius, Frederick: Sea Drift, Herbert Flietner, baritone, NDR Hamburg, Carl Schurcht, conductor; Robert Volkman: Overture to Shakespeare's Richard III, für grosses Orchester, Op. 68, RSO Stuttgart, Carl Schurcht, conductor. WELTE -- Recordings (dericving from Freiburg, Welte Collection).
  - Various works, 1992 March 17 (Box 27, Item 12)
    Delius, Frederick: Announcement; In Meerestreiben. Herbert Fleicher, baritone. NDR Hamburg, Carl Schuricht, conductor. Equalized copy, Yale HSR-1, stereo master. Includes musical and technical information in storage case.
  - Family and Roosevelt, Einstein, and King Lear, 1942-1946, undated (Box 27, Item 13)
    King Lear with Orson Welles, broadcast 1946 Sep 13 with Mercury Theater.
  - Family, 1962, undated (Box 27, Item 14)
    Second stage of digital processing.
  - Frauenliebe -- H. B., undated (Box 27, Item 15)
    Robert Schimann: Frauenliebe und leben; Helen Boatwright, soprano [?].
  - Giordano, Umberto: Fedora, 1997 March 9 (Box 27, Item 16)
    Mirella Freni, soprano, Placido Domingo, tenor. Metropolitan Opera broadcast.
  - Gregorian chant, undated
    - Original transfer II (Box 27, Item 17)
      Schütz [?].
    - Disc I (Box 28, Item 18)
    - Disc 2 (Box 28, Item 19)
  - Haas and Taskin, undated (Box 28, Item 20)
    Arthur Haas, harpsichord, and Taskin make harpsichord [?]. Music of Johann Jacob Froberger, François Couperin, and Johann Sebastian Bach.
  - H. B. rehearsal -- Helen Boatwright [?], undated (Box 28, Item 21)
  - Hindemith, Paul: Das Marienleben, 1969 July 3 (Box 28, Item 22)
    Helen Boatwright, soprano, Frederick Marvin, piano. Inlcudes musical and technical information in storage case.
  - Hindemith, Paul: When lilacs last in the dooryard bloomed (Requiem), 1956 April 15 (Box 28, Item 23)
    Helen Boatwright, soprano, Margaret Tobias, mezzo-soprano, Banjamin de Laoche, baritone. Smith College Glee Club, Yale Glee Club, Yale University Orchestra, Howard Boatwright, conductor. Woolsey Hall performance.
  - Ives, Charles: Various songs, 1969 November 2 (Box 28, Item 24)
    Includes talk by John Kirkpatrick. Helen Boatwright, soprano, John Kirkpatrick, piano. [Syracuse University] concert.
  - Marvin: Soler -- Frederick Marvin (piano) [?], undated (Box 28, Item 25)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus; Paul Hindemith, 1970 October 5 (Box 28, Item 26)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus: Eine kleine Deutsche Kantate, KV 619; Paul Hindemith: Das Marienleben. Helen Boatwright, soprano, Frederick Marvin, piano. Includes musical information in storage case.
  - Overtone no. 6 and 9 (OV 6 and 9), undated (Box 28, Item 27)
    Overtone no. 6 (OV 6): Dietrich Buxtehude -- Herr, auf dich traue ich; Singet dem Herrn; Lauda Sion; Jesu, meine Freude. Helen Boatwright, soprano. Choir of St. Thomas Church. Overtone no. 9 (OV 9): Johann Rosenmüller, side A; In te, Domine; Die Augen des Herrn. Howard Boatwright, conductor; Yale HSR-1, mono master, second and third digital stage. Includes musical and technical information inside storage case.
  - Overtone no. 9 and 1 (OV 9 and 1), 1962, undated (Box 28, Item 28)
    Overtone no. 9 (OV 9), side B: Johann Rosenmüller -- Confitebor tibi, Domine; Nunc dimittis. Overtone no. 1 (OV 1): Alessandro Scarlatti -- St. John Passio, Blake Stern, Evangelist, David Laurent, Jesus [et al.]. Member of the Yale University Orchestra, Howard Boatwright, conductor. Yale HSR-1, mono master, second digital stage.
  - Overtone no. 10 (OV 10), 1955
    Quincy Porter -- Symphony no. 1, Concerto Concertante for Two Pianos and Orchestra; Dance in Three Time. Andre Terrasse, piano, Jean-Leon Cohen, piano, André Charlin, conductor. Originally recorded 1955 Jun.
    - Tape 1 of 3 (Box 28, Item 29)
      Digital transfer created 1995 Dec 5. Includes musical and technical information in storage case.
    - Tape 2 of 3 (Box 28, Item 30)
      1. Copy of digital original 2. master with reverb. Includes technical information in storage case.
    - Tape 3 of 3 (Box 28, Item 31)
      1. Reverb master 2. Copy of digital master. Includes technical information in storage case.
  - St. Olaf's Choir: Fiftieth anniversary recording from Mercury stereo record; Yale HSR-1: first stereo version (Box 28, Item 32)
  - St. Olav's [Olaf's] Choir: Various choral works (Box 28, Item 33)
    Original copies. Mono. Yale HSR-1 and 2, fifth stage.
  - St. Thomas' Choir: Johann Sebastian Bach (Box 28, Item 34)
    Christ lag in Todesbanden BWV 4; Wachet auf BWV 140; Adeste Fidelis. Helen Boatwright, soprano et al., Howard Boatwright, conductor.
  - Tunder, Franz; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, 1956–1957
    Tunder, Franz: Cantatas, Helen Boatwright, soprano et al., Howard Boatwright, conductor (1957 May 5). Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart: Exsultate, Jubilate! KV 165; Sub tuum praesidium KV 198, Helen Boatwright, soprano, Blake Stern, tenor; Chamber Orchestra of the Yale School of Music, Howard Boatwright, conductor. Performance 1956 Mar 1.
    - Tape 1, 1956–1957 (Box 29, Item 35)
    - Tunder's Cantatas only, 1957 (Box 29, Item 36)
  - Yale Collegium Musicum concert, 1948 July 20
    Includes a composite mass, German lieder, and French Danseries. Yale HSR-1.
    - Master (Box 29, Item 37)
    - Second generation digital restoration copy (Box 29, Item 38)
    - Extra copy (Box 29, Item 39)
  - Yale Collegium Musicum concert at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1951
    Includes music of various Renaissance composers listed in storage case.
    - Master tape (Box 29, Item 40)
    - A to D master no. 1 (Box 29, Item 41)
      Includes techinical information in storage case.
    - Second digital stage, master (Box 29, Item 42)
      Includes recordings from Sprague Hall concert of same repertoire.
    - Second digital stage, master (Box 29, Item 43)
      Copy [?].
    - Second digital stage (Box 29, Item 44)
      Yale HSR-2 final master. Includes technical information in storage case.
    - Alternate copies from discs 2 and 3 (Box 29, Item 45)
    - Copy (Box 29, Item 46)
  - Yale Collegium Musicum concert, 1953 May 14
    Johann Sebastian Bach: Singet dem Herrn ein neus Lied, BWV 225. Works by Jan Ladislav Dussek, Frederick Marvin, piano, Paul Hindemith, conductor. Includes music of various Renaissance composers listed in storage case.
    - First stage digital re-mastering (Box 29, Item 47)
      Copy of digital master. Includes Renaissance repertoire in storage case.
    - Second digital stage, Master (Box 29, Item 48)
    - Second digital stage (Box 29, Item 49)
      Copy. Includes musical and technical information in storage case.
    - Third digital stage, Master (Box 29, Item 50)
    - Third digital stage (Box 29, Item 51)
      Digital copy.
    - Copy-protect noise bursts (version) (Box 30, Item 52)
  - Yale HSR - 1, undated
    Digital copy of master recording.
    - Original (Box 30, Item 53)
    - Digital copy (Box 30, Item 54)
  - Yale HSR - 1 and 2, undated (Box 30, Item 55)
    Outtakes.
  - Yale HSR - 2
    - Master (Box 30, Item 56)
    - Master (Box 30, Item 57)
    - Digital copy (Box 30, Item 58)
    - Final copy [?], 1992 September 29 (Box 30, Item 59)